## **APPLICATION LATTER**

## **FATHI OMER ABIB**

Mobile+252-63-4041368, +252-65-4041368

Email: fathiccie@gmail.com.

Address: Daloodho 150 STREET HAGEISA-SOMALILAND.

29, 12, 2022



**RE: Network Engineering/ Sever mangment** 

#### Dear.

I am excited to have the opportunity to apply for this position. I have always been fascinated by Networking, Windows Adminstrator and other Technologies like , Troubleshooting , tinkering with them and exploring their inner workings ever since I was a child. Learning to program opened up a whole new world to me, and I knew that I wanted to hone my skills at handling computer hardware and software to the highest level so that I could and devote my life to working with them. I believe that I have the determination and creative intelligence necessary to fit into the role of Network Administrator.

Though I have no formal experience as a Network Administrator, I have experience working as a back-end (Troubleshooting Networks) programming and setting up and configuring office networks. I am intimately familiar with Linux, Linux Server operating systems and Windows Server (2012 2016.).

Further More, I have also CCNA Certifications from **Cisco** (CSCO13671975) **and** also passed the New CCNA 200-301. High Technicality and more training of this field with passing these certification exams gave me considerable hands-on experience maintaining networks and running security checks on them.

Thank you very much for your time and consideration, and I look forward to setting up an interview. To be able to join the Crossover team and dedicate my programming abilities to solving stimulating and challenging technical problems would be a dream come true.

Sincerely

Fathi Omer



### **CURRICULUM VITEA**

### **ABOUT ME**

I am an enthusiastic and high-achieving Bachelor of Software Engineering, CCNA holder and Candidate of CCNP exam in this month. I have exceptional technical and analytical skills, with experience in Software Engineering, data analysis, database management, information system support, security, network and server support, business analysis, enterprise application integration, program configuration, testing and evaluation, which I have gained in various analyst/programmer roles.

### **Professional Experience**

## January 2019 To PRESENT: - Technox Institute as a Trainer and Student

My role and duties at **Technox Institute** are included as followings:

- Training.
- Translating the students and Teacher.
- Maintaining the Network.

### **December 2017 To PRESENT: - MY ENTERPENEUR**

- Trader in Stock Market.
- High Typing Mavis and writing Books and also Letters to the LAW people.
- Teacher Assistant.

**December 2018 To PRESENT: -** Forex and Trading International Markets.

March 2019 to Dec 2019: - Internship at Total Fuel Station (Network Management)

**FEB 2021 to Present:** - Ministry of Employment social affairs and Family (MESAF)

- Web Technician
- Data Entry With the foreigners work-permit
- IT and Technician

## **SEP 2021 to Present: -** Lecturer and Consultant In ABAAL COLLAGE (ICT)

 Teaching and Trainer in Microsoft Office and Basic Computer Needs such like Networking, Troubleshooting, and other things.

# SEP 2022 to Dec: - SYSTESA Smart Technology Company

- Managing savers and all the network like controlling everything that enters the network and the out the network.
- Also have part time work making software by using PHP, JS, HTML, CSS.

## **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND: -**

Sept 2015 to jun 2019: - Secondary school at Noradin Secondary School

<u>January 2017 to Sep 2018: -</u> Diploma of ICT at Institute of TISQAAD Computer science 2018

<u>January 2018 to Sep 2021:</u> Bachelors of Software Engineering and IT at University of Abaarso Tech 2021

<u>December 2020 to Dec 2024: -</u> Cisco certified with the New CCNA 200-301 (CSCO13671975)

### WORKSHOP/ SEMINAR ATTENDED:

Duration	Award	Institution
November 2019	CCNA including New CCNA 200-301	Technox ACADEMY
January 2018	Training of CCTV camera and Freelance	TISQAAD Institute of Computer Science
March 2019	LAW OFFICE	Faatax Public Notary

#### **LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY**

- Somali Native
- English Fluent
- Arabic Good

## **SKILLS**

- Skilled at:
- Microsoft Office 365
- OSPF, EIGRP,BGP
- RIP, IGRP, STATIC ROUTE
- ASA FIREWALLS
- Java<sup>TM</sup>
- Networking (NEW CCNA 200-301)
- Security Consultant
- SQL

- Software development
- Project management
- JavaScript<sup>TM</sup>
- ODOO software (Open Source)
- Programming
- Troubleshooting Systems and Networks
- Windows Server
- HTML AND CSS
- C SHARP
- VB.NET
- WORDPRESS
- Microsoft office (word, Excel, Access and Power Point)
- Microsoft project management
- Teamwork, and Problem solving
- Good Communication skills
- Commitment to work according to organizations vision, mission, and values
- Cultural, gender, race, nationality and religious sensitivity

## PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

- Good organizer and communicator
- Strong mathematical skills.
- Attention to detail.
- Knowledge of proper cash handling procedures.
- Comfortable working with diverse groups (different age groups)
- Cultural, gender, religion, race, nationality and age sensitivity and adaptability
- Creative problem solving

### **REFERENCES**

**ANJUM MUNIIR AHMED (Master of Technox)** 

Tell: 0636088365

Tell: 0091-7411677634

**Mowlid Mohamed Omer (CEO OF SYSTESA)** 

Tell: +252 63 4000547

**GARYAQAN OMER (LAWYER)** 

TELL: +252 63 4478031